<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Kyle Fiedler</title>
		<description>Inside the mind of a boring person</description>
		<link>http://kylefiedler.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://kylefiedler.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Life prospective</title>
				<description>&lt;iframe src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/9NjKgV65fpo'&gt;video&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s amazing how quickly things can get out of prospective. It&amp;#8217;s easy to see all the bad that you have in life and none of the good. It is really inspiring that such young people can demonstrate such maturity in the face of such a young death. If I can be half of the person Zach is, I will really proud of myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/prospective</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/prospective</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Thinking about creativity</title>
				<description>&lt;iframe allowFullScreen='allowFullScreen' frameborder='0' src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/18913413 '&gt;video&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;iframe allowFullScreen='allowFullScreen' frameborder='0' src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/45162748 '&gt;video&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been doing a lot of thinking about creativity and its juxtaposition to making. I have always hated the thought that I am a capitol C &amp;#8220;Creative&amp;#8221;. I don&amp;#8217;t really believe such people exist. Really everyone is creative, and most of the more creative people I have met are&amp;rswuo;t in a design or arts field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always felt like my ideas were. What I always considered myself was a doer and maker. Where other people had better ideas then me I was much more willing and capable to make those ideas or convey those ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After watching the two presentations in this post on having ideas and working through the ideas, I feel validated in that thinking. Take a look at both they are certainly worth the watch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/creativity</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/creativity</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Making analogies</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m getting quite tired of analogies for how we as web designers work. Maybe its just the context that I always hear them in but they always seem whiney. Designing for a screen is different. It&amp;#8217;s not print design, it&amp;#8217;s not product design, it&amp;#8217;s not architecture. We can and should learn a lot from these industries but we shouldn&amp;#8217;t rely on them to dictate our profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing for a screen is different. The sooner that you accept that the sooner we can move on as an industry. Stop complaining. Start doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/analogies</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/analogies</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Countdown to Opening Day</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Screen shot of Opening day countdown' src='/images/posts/opening-day.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a small little project while watching the Superbowl that counts down to MLB Opening Day. The waiting is the hardest part&amp;#8230; &lt;a href='/experiments/baseball-countdown.html'&gt;Check it out here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/baseball-countdown</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/baseball-countdown</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Using black and gray</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things my art teacher taught me when I was painting was never use black paint. This is because you&amp;#8217;ll never actually see real black. It simply doesn&amp;#8217;t exist. In reality, what seems black is really a deep blue, brown, red or combo of those colors. Anyway you look at it, the black has some tone to it. So I never painted with true black paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been trying to stop using gray and black in all of my design work too. I&amp;#8217;ve started to realize that when I use strait gray or black the design seems lifeless, fake and unhappy. This is because the black has no real tone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/using-black</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/using-black</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A day in India</title>
				<description>&lt;iframe allowFullScreen='allowFullScreen' frameborder='0' src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/58313264 '&gt;video&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href='http://vimeo.com/58313264'&gt;A Day in India&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me really want to visit India. There are some beautiful scenes and what look like interesting people. It also makes me really hungry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/india-food</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/india-food</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The million year view of design</title>
				<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been attempting to look beyond the assumptions and biases that frame my thinking and find ideas that integrate and unify design as a practice, method, and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href='http://unicornmeet.com/2013/01/universal-design/'&gt;Chad Mazzola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting reflection on writing and design. Sums up better than I could some of my thinking over the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/million-year-view</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/million-year-view</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>This years goals</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not one for resultuions so to speak but I do like to revisit my current goals everyonce and a while and the beginning of the year is as good of a time as any. I figured it was time to look over, update and add new goals to the list. What follow is what I have currently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take lots of photos&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be more social&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Become a better writer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Make less decisions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be more fiscally responsible&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be less fiscally responsible&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Draw a lot&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;More water less tea&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Make art again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/goals</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/goals</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Fresh Starts</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There is something thrilling about a fresh start. It&amp;#8217;s a blank canvas waiting for paint. You get to define what is to come and discard what came in the past. There is now space to rethink process, and analyze every moment through it. It allows for more growth and better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But starting fresh is hard work. Usually, its easier to use the scaffolding that has been established. To build off whats there or fix something that is broken. It&amp;#8217;s a rare case when it&amp;#8217;s not. Fresh starts are time consuming, stressful, and you&amp;#8217;re not guaranteed a better outcome than what you had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;#8217;t posted on this site for quite some time and throughout that time I wished I hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped. What I saw though, when I looked back was a platform that didn&amp;#8217;t reflect me as a designer, developer or person. This to me was a glaring problem. What is this site if not a reflection of who I am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started the redesign, I found myself lost. I couldn&amp;#8217;t get to a solution that I found acceptable to the goals which I set out to solve. At points I lost sight of those goals too, which made the process long and more drawn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel what I have now is finally at a state that I can accept. I, again, have a platform to get better at writing and a playground for designing around that writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heres to fresh starts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/fresh-starts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/fresh-starts</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The ABC of Architects</title>
				<description>&lt;iframe allowFullScreen='allowFullScreen' frameborder='0' src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/56974716 '&gt;video&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href='http://vimeo.com/56974716'&gt;The ABC of Architects on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A uniquely animated short film on architects from A&amp;#8211;Z.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://kylefiedler.com/blog/abcs-of-architects</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylefiedler.com/blog/abcs-of-architects</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
